

Deinichenko Ivan

Senior Software Developer

Location: Belgrade, Serbia

Date of birth: 27.05.1989 (34 years old)

Phone number: +381638096675

E-mail: deathklaat89@gmail.com

Overall experience

More than 10 years experience in web and mobile game development as frontend / fullstack. Have expertise with browsers API, social networks API, Google API (e.g. Firebase), REST. Worked at some Unity 3D projects as C# developer. Have backend expertise including PHP, MySQL, Memcached, Redis, Yii, Yii2, Codelgniter, Laravel.

For several years I partially worked as a team leader in the game development team. Meetings, Jira, project planning and estimations.

Skills area

- Software development
- Object-oriented architecture and design
- Front-end development
- HTML games development
- Unity games development
- Documentation creation
- Cross-browser markup/development
- Third-party widgets integration
- Code quality assurance (refactoring, code review)

Technical domains

Languages	JavaScript ES 5/6+, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, C#, PHP
Frameworks and libraries	VueJS 2/3, Nuxt 2/3, Vuex, Vue Router, Vuetify, Vue Bootstrap, Lodash, jQuery, Phaser, Spine, Axios, TweenJS, ChartJS
Technologies	Social API (e.g. Facebook, VK), Firebase API (remote config, realtime database), Browser APIs
DBMS	MySQL
Tools	Git, Jira, Confluence, Bash, Webpack, NPM, Composer, Yarn, Brew, Docker, Figma, Photoshop, Browsers DevTools
IDEs	VSCode, PhpStorm

Education

2006-2012 - Petrozavodsk State University, Math faculty, Information system and technologies - Specialist

Languages

- Russian Native
- English Intermediate (B1-B2)
- Serbian A1

Notable projects

Multiplayer Solitaire Card Game

A game of cards for multiple players. Single elimination tournament. Every round two players battle each other to solve the solitaire game faster. Players also can use boosters to slow down the enemy or get benefits for themselves.

Technologies: HTML 5, Canvas, CSS 3, SASS, JavaScript ES5, jQuery, AJAX, REST API, Webpack, LongPolling.

Responsibility: Complete development of frontend of the project. Optimization and refactoring project for mobile devices. Migration from divs game architecture to canvas (We found that the divs one was slow).

Text and graphic novel game

Mobile game for Play Market and App Store. Users can choose a novel from a list and read it by tapping on the screen. Non-linear storylines depend on the user's choices.

Technologies: VueJS, Vuex, Vuex Persisted State, Vue Router, Vue Draggable, Vuetify, Vue SVG Icon, Vue i18n, Vue Touch Events, ES6+, Axios, SASS, Webpack, npm, git.

Third party libraries e.g. amplitude and yandex metrics.

Codelgniter, Laravel, PHP7, MySQL, Redis.

Responsibility: Complete development of the project. Architecture design, markup, frontend and backend functionality. Database design and implementation. Performance optimization. Integration of third-party plugins such as billing, notifications, localization, metrics. Migration from Codelgniter to Laravel as backend architecture refactoring.

Farm-like game (Hay day for example)

Multiplayer farming simulator where you can plant crops and trees, sell products, raise animals, enhance your farm and city, etc.

Technologies: ES5, ES6, HTML5, Canvas, CSS3, SASS, gulp, Spine (JS), WebSockets, Lodash, jQuery.

Responsibility: Support and update project's functionality, generate new content ideas, create new activities and locations for players. Write quests texts, calculate in-game economy, get feedback from the community, implement new functionality. Collaborate with the design and QA department. Do not forget about KPIs. Performance optimization. Cross-browser support, mobile support.

Work experience

Acronis (Belgrade, Serbia), Nov 2022 - Present

Position: Senior Vue JS Developer

Responsibilities:

Development of the acronis.com frontend part. Tasks estimation, code review, support for old functions, implementation of new functionality, search engine optimization.

Technologies: Figma, HTML, CSS, NuxtJS, VueJS, 3rd-party integrations.

Noveo (St. Petersburg, Russia), Feb 2022 - Nov 2022

Position: Middle+ Vue JS Developer

Responsibilities:

Development of frontend side of outsource/outstaff applications, Projects estimation, Code Review.

Technologies: Figma, HTML, CSS, NuxtJS + CompositionAPI, 3rd-party integrations.

Startup Company, May 2021 - Jun 2022 (St. Petersburg, Russia)

Position: Unity / Frontend Developer

Responsibilities: Development of visual novels for Play Market and App Store based on Unity3D Engine. Integration of billing, notifications, metrics, social plugins etc. Development of project's administration SPA based on VueJS. **Technologies**: Unity 3D, C#, OOP, SOLID, Logcat, JarResolver. JS ES6+, VueJS, Vuex, Vue Router, Vue Bootstrap, Firebase API.

Startup Company (St. Petersburg, Russia), Jun 2020 - May 2021

Position: Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities: Development of text novels for Play Market based on HTML5, VueJS and WebView. Development of project's administration SPA based on VueJS.

Technologies: Git, JavaScript ES6+, VueJS, Vuex, Vuetify, Vue Router, Vue i18n, Vue Draggable, Vue SVG Icons, Webpack, npm, composer, docker, Laravel, Codelgniter, MySQL, Redis, CI/CD.

Publisher company (St. Petersburg, Russia), Sep 2019 - Jun 2020

Position: Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities: Development of text novels for Play Market based on HTML5, VueJS and WebView. Development of project's administration SPA based on VueJS.

Technologies: Git, JavaScript ES6+, VueJS, Vuex, Vuetify, Vue Router, Vue i18n, Vue Draggable, Vue SVG Icons, Webpack, npm, composer, docker, Laravel, Codelgniter, MySQL, Redis, CI/CD.

Publisher company (St. Petersburg, Russia), Sep 2019 - Jun 2020

Position: Unity Developer

Responsibilities: Development of mobile games for Play Market and App Store in hyper-casual genre. Core functionality of games, integration of billing, localization, notifications, ads providers, socials etc.

Technologies: Git, Unity 3D, C#, REST API, OOP, SOLID, Figma, Logcat, XCode.

Social Platform (St. Petersburg, Russia), Oct 2018 - Sep 2019

Position: Frontend Developer

Responsibilities: Development and support of HTML 5 canvas games. Match 3, some clickers, arcades, mahjong, puzzles etc. Additionally refactoring and optimization of the platform's legacy.

Technologies: Git, JavaScript ES6+, WebSockets, Webpack, npm, HTML5 + Canvas, CSS 3, SASS.

Social Platform (St. Petersburg, Russia), Oct 2017 - Oct 2018

Position: Frontend Developer

Responsibilities: Development of new functionality for farm-like games on social platforms. Supports and updates actual functionality, communicates with the community, reruns regular activities, creates the new ones.

Technologies: Git, Javascript ES5, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Gulp, WebSockets, Lodash, Social API, REST API, Photoshop. Partially PHP, Yii 2, MySQL.

Game Development Company (Petrozavodsk, Russia), Oct 2012 - Oct 2017

Position: Full Stack Developer, Team Lead

Responsibilities:

As a developer: Development of HTML games. Markup, frontend logic, backend logic, database design.

As a team lead: meet-ups / stand-ups, communication between product owners and development team, Jira tracking, sprints planning, tasks and project estimates. Consulting, research of new ideas and technologies, takes part in product brainstorms.

Technologies: Git, JavaScript ES5, HTML5, CSS3, Canvas, jQuery, REST API, PHP5, Yii, MySQL, Photoshop, WebSockets/Long Polling, Social networks APIs, Unity 3D (partially, last year).